Marko Grešak

Senior Front End Engineer

▶ Ljubljana, Slovenia▶ marko@gresak.io▶ gresak.io

Summary

A senior front end engineer with a passion to deliver great products that users love to use. Expert in JavaScript and things related. Web development enthusiast for the last 8 years, exploring and working with React for the last four years.

Excited to always learn and try out new things, to improve and to share knowledge. Taking teaching as the best way to explore and get a deep knowledge of a topic and to help everyone around expand their knowledge.

Work experience

Senior Front End Engineer

2018-07 - Present

Prezly

The main responsibility was working in a small, fully remote team of experienced developers to build the core product.

- Building a custom rich text editor experience which powers the CMS (Slate slatejs.org). The focus was building a user-friendly editing experience and connecting different parts and features of the platform as rich embeds inside the editor content.
- Working with designers to convert the design into specs and into the final implementation. Testing out different ideas with the designers to produce the best solution for the users.
- Improve UX, performance, and a11y of public-facing newsrooms generated for the customers.
- Introduce TypeScript and drive adoption. One year later, a bit over 50% of the codebase is in TypeScript (~50k lines of code). This also included educating the team with a prior bad experience of TypeScript (due to poor implementation) on how to efficiently use TypeScript. This change led to fewer mistakes in the shipped code, faster development, and more satisfied developers.
- Implementing a custom data grid, focusing on customizability, good performance, and good experience on mobile devices.
- Driving the adoption of React hooks, showing the team how to use hooks.
- Profiling and optimizing the SCSS code to reduce the output size by 70% and improve build speed by 50%.

Senior Front End Engineer

2018-04 - 2018-06

D. Labs

In addition to the previous responsibilities, lead the front end development part of custom data exploration and dashboard web app:

- Worked with the product manager in communication with the stakeholders, and a designer to create an implementation based on goals and initial low-fi wireframes.
- Worked with back end engineers to help architect the API to support dashboards to overview the progress of teachers and students in online school classrooms.

Front End Engineer

2016-06 - 2018-03

D. Labs

Working on Angular.js (1.5) and React.js web apps:

- Updated Angular is app's UI to improve the responsiveness of the web app (custom behaviour on mobile).
- Various bug fixes and performance improvements within the Angular.js app.
- Developed responsive messaging UI within Angular.js (port from a legacy system).
- Migrated Angular.js project's (ignored) JSHint config to ESLint, fixed errors and adding lint as a build step.
- Designed and developed a configurable bot running on Node.js responsible for merging branches on GitHub based on team's custom git flow.
- Lead a rewrite of content creation app to use React with Redux.js, which was previously server-side Rails app with some React (without Redux) mixed in. Responsible for setting up the app config, app architecture

decisions, developed many of the core features, maintaining project code quality.

- Teaching team members and employees working on other projects about React.
- Working on optimisation of webpack config to reduce the build time and increase developer's productivity.
- Updated E2E tests projects to use TypeScript, fixed failing tests after a major update, added more tests to cover more user flows and previously caught regressions.
- Added custom user analytics within the Angular.js app: set KPIs, added event tracking.

(The position ended because of a promotion to Senior Front End Engineer.)

Software Engineer

2016-02 - 2016-05

Toptal

Worked on various freelance projects using React, usually with Redux.js (depended on client's project setup).

(The position ended because of focus on CS studies.)

Genialis

Worked with a team using Angular.js on a web app for visualization of gene data:

- Developed UI to assign permissions to users.
- Developed a component for visualizing large images using tiled images (provided by an API).
- Updated graph components responsible for visualizing RNA-seq data.

(Worked as a student. The position ended because of focus on CS studies.)

Full Stack Developer

2014-07 - 2014-09

3TAV

Upgraded user request ticket management webpage from last year (previous position):

- Developed a responsive webpage using Bootstrap.
- Added XHR requests for more dynamic webpage content.

(Worked as a student. The position ended because of focus on CS studies.)

Full Stack Developer

2013-07 - 2013-09

3TAV

Git

Developed a user request ticket management webpage in ASP.NET MVC.

(Worked as a student. The position ended because of focus on CS studies.)

Skills	
JavaScript	Strong knowledge of JavaScript with object-oriented and functional programming approaches. Knowledge of ES2015+ features and keeping up with new developments.
React	Strong knowledge of React and the library's API, including hooks. Knowledge of relevant libraries to create responsive single-page applications.
TypeScript	Experience using TypeScript in Node.js and React projects. Introduced TypeScript to an existing large project.
CSS	Very good knowledge of CSS and how to use it to develop responsive web pages. Experience working with CSS preprocessors, such as Sass and Less. Experience with CSS-in-JS approaches using libraries css-modules and styled-components/emotion.
Node.js	Experience with writing Node.js scripts to work with IO and web requests.

with libgit2 (via nodegit).

Strong knowledge of git CLI and how git works under the hood. Worked

Back End Development

Some experience with Node.js, Ruby on Rails, and PHP. Lacking practice because it's not my day-to-day responsibility, but I'm not afraid to dive into the code to explore and understand it or to fix simple bugs.

Languages

Slovenian (native), English (proficient), Croatian (intermediate)

Education

BSc in Computer and Information Science

2013 - 2018

The Faculty of Computer and Information Science (Ljubljana, Slovenia) https://fri.uni-lj.si/en/study-programme/computer-and-information-science

Final thesis: Assessing the suitability of Elm language for developing web applications

References

Available on request.

Created with **TVisualCV**